Good day, everyone. Let's talk about a view from the ground floor. Now, we have been talking about the AI space, I guess, since the beginning. I remember back, it wasn't that long ago, 2000, 2001, started reading some study research papers out of Stanford, talking about artificial intelligence, of course, and that's everybody's exciting point, at least today.
what we're watching is a lot of change and it seems like people are pretty much in agreement
that there's going to be this uncomfortable uncomfortable moment uh time that we're going
to be going through it i did a video this morning that i think encapsulate this this a little bit
better but i do want to talk about where AI is from where most of us are standing now a lot of
you have retirements perfect a lot of my friends spent enough time at the police department to be
able to get that and that's fantastic I'm still working and I will continue my drive and my quest
I think forever because this feels very important to me just like when you if you're watching this
you're a police officer you did sign up for a particular reason to protect and to serve
at least most of us did there were some that kind of like that that whole adrenaline rush
and they were complete adrenaline junkies yeah I get that that's that's part of that mix and it's
sometimes people that didn't originally start because of that really did enjoy that but moving
from there looking at where we are today again now I'm thinking yeah there's nobody that's developing
any kind of a good idea or theory behind trying to make this quote-unquote transition a little
more smoother so i've decided to start something called a moonshot moonshot is there's different
organizations that develop these ideas where they basically they're shooting towards the moon and
trying to fix and heal things and there's been you know billions and millions of dollars millions of
dollars in prize money for people that have built out good moonshots you know solving a particular
disease or trying to de-plasticize the oceans and these sorts of things trying to reduce carbon
emissions greenhouse effect okay that's all good but what about the people that are on the ground
floor which is most everybody watching looking up at the people running all the companies what if
we built our moonshot and had the people buy into it figuring out the best way to make this
quote unquote uncomfortable transition because that's all i'm seeing as of now people are talking
about well so they they they lavish you with all of the pleasantries it's going to be fantastic
it's going to be amazing everything's going to be just lovely perfect and everybody's everything's
going to have its place and artificial intelligence is going to have us all rise to an entirely
different level in the world and in society great great great great but in when they say that
people from the labs now and these are all with specific reasons they're calling out and saying
well you know we need you to regulate us that's probably there's other reasons for that besides
them really being concerned that there's a safety issue some of them are pushing this forward
because they number one don't want to be liable if something goes wrong which this is that
uncomfortableness that people talk about it's going to be a little unpleasant and then the
other end of this thing is of course they want to create the moat so no other no other person
or people that have made a decision to build out AI technology that potentially could compete with
OpenAI's ChatGPT or Anthropic's Claude or microsoft's co-pilot or you know xAI's Grok
or xai's grok or whatever they're calling that company now super xai super intelligence i guess
but so nothing could compete so if there is regulatory measures taken with the AI frontier
labs yeah good luck somebody coming in and trying to start it's like trying to start a bank good
luck with starting a bank and especially if you're in europe trying to start a bank i i just don't
know if that's even possible but looking at the way that this technology is being built the view
from the ground floor looks a little bit different because they're telling us it's going to be
uncomfortable so who's telling us that it's going to be uncomfortable people that are set now these
people they might have some kind of a retirement but it's not pension based it's most of the folks
didn't do 30 years 35 years as a cop or as a firefighter or as a nurse or as fill in the blank
of whatever type of employment would get a CalPERS or some kind of other pension system that would
pay them in so that money isn't really theirs that money is well yours but that money potentially if
you start paying a little bit more attention might be used to buy into this technology and as long as
the technology keeps going that's great but looking at the historical record i know history who wants
to mess with history well looking at the railroads the the venture capitalists those are the people
that were watching on moonshots and these other endeavors they have the right connections they
went to the right college they were in the right dorm room or the right smart person and you know
have opportunities so you give you know ten thousand dollars then you walk out with four
hundred billion dollars kind of an investment strategy with venture capitalists but typically
the walking in money the seed money the money that the pension funds don't get access to the money
that most of us don't get i i knew a cop um last name of armor and john mentioned that he had an
opportunity to buy into Jordache Jordache genes at some point and john had a lot of interesting
stories like that this was one of them and he thought it was a stupid idea if if memory served
this this story was 91 i heard this but maybe but venture capitalists they don't think AI is
a stupid idea at all they're they're into it they're going into AI all in all together now
Now, how does that look for the people that have pensions? Well, if you go back to the railroads, the people that paid for the railroads originally, they lost a lot.
The people that came in after that, when it basically completely hit the ground floor, they're the ones that made the money.
with the internet you had the original investors into it the private the venture capitalists and this is kind of reminiscent in most markets where you have big tech or some kind of massive
innovative idea you have those early people in they're able to cash out at a particular point
these stories exist and they're able to walk out and then other people go in and pick it up at the
time and that's when it collapses usually and then those other people the guys that got out
now they go back in because it's pennies on the dollar and they create even more I don't know if
that is this but they keep talking about it's going to be a little uncomfortable of course job
loss and not having food to eat that would be very uncomfortable so the people that are saying it's
going to be a little uncomfortable I'm curious if it's going to be uncomfortable for them yes yes
having to watch people starve that's got to be horrible but what if you're on the receiving end
of being the one that's starving. So I propose this. So we have moonshots to be able to protect
us from global warming, moonshots for potentially curing disease and cancers and these sorts of
things. Moonshots to paint a better picture of the AI future for everyone. That's another prize
that they're awarding. Instead of movies like The Terminator, instead of movies like The Matrix,
coming out with movies that are very much supportive of an AI future about how it's going
to love us all and take care of us and want the best for us and so we don't fight with each other
we don't fight with ourselves and we just live this better than awesome age and wonder of abundance
we have all of those things which okay i'm all in i i don't really believe you you have a couple
crowds out there you have the doomer end of it right they're saying that it's gonna it's gonna
wipe us all out then you have other people that think it's a bubble thinks it's it's all nonsense
and it's really not going to go anywhere i'm i'm not in either one of those really AI for me used
as a hammer used as a tool in my helping businesses and being completely up front with
them i'm not there to replace your staff and if that's your goal then probably going to need
somebody else the world though is looking at it for money and if they can replace staff and save
them money and bring in an AI that's able to do exactly what the staff can for you know almost
free then why should they not well they should not because it's gonna cause issues with the people
that they're getting rid of i think my my opinion but then the argument is well yeah but if if we
keep these people some smart cat's going to come in from stage left and it's going to formulate an
entire company that's that does have a head but kind of employee less except for AI so AI will
be doing all the job of everybody and it's really going to be without the head of the company the
head will be there for potentially liability purposes unless you're argentina and that one's
already kind of moved on but back to the idea the the Moonshot for the transitional
uncomfortableness that we are going to feel you ask the people that are saying it's going to be
uncomfortable where are they in life who is it going to be uncomfortable for let's let's get
that laid out who is this and what do they have to lose when it gets uncomfortable i would venture to
say besides having to watch people suffer and i know i'm saying that very crass but to them i
don't know if that's as meaningful as they themselves suffering i don't think but that's
that's where the alignment is so besides that where where do they suffer they're set their
generations are set because they were the early adopters into the technology they've been right
place right time right level of intelligence right focus they've built this empire so instead of
making Moonshots the way that they are to develop movies that make AI look better and that's great
i'm all for that future my gosh wouldn't it be amazing if we all lived in a complete age of
abundance without having that we were safe we were secure we weren't being programmed in a way where
where now we're being controlled and mass manipulated.
Yeah, like that doesn't exist.
But we were able to have our freedom, our free of thought,
almost like that movie with Salma Hayek, right?
Kind of a future like that,
something where we can all agree we have all we need,
we have more than we need,
and we're very happy in that world.
Why not developing an idea
to be able to have this transition be a moonshot itself
with a prize award and everything else?
How can we fix that? Because this isn't the scale of the revolutions before the industrial and so
on. This is a much larger scale and this has the potential to happen a lot faster and the payoff
could come a lot quicker, but the payoff is probably being targeted at the people that have
all of the power, all of the control and the venture capitalists that have gone in.
and are they really going to use the people that have invested 30 and 50 years into a business to get a pension are they really going to take that money and go all in and then what if that mechanism
fails on the other end of it what if AI turns out to be somewhat not a flop but basically gets
devalued because of something that occurs whatever that scenario would look like then all the pension
systems go bust and then the people that had income that they were depending on now they don't
and it's a question because i don't know there's plenty of people talking about this in all spaces
and again i'm not a doomer i think this is fantastic i want this to work it's it's those
words of it's going to be uncomfortable that i can't grasp what does that look like is it and
is it one person yeah out of six or seven billion that that sucks for that person
but is it a quarter of the people a tenth of the people then how do we fix that if we do put in a
moonshots transition and we do build this out so it makes the transition seamless with the speed
of way the technology is because we can't fathom exponentials we can't fathom how fast this is
going to go we can't fathom exponential growth in intelligence maybe that's the trick but to bet on
that without really having the answer that because we can't see it nobody can only super intelligence
can and for them to try to explain it to us is like us trying to explain to a whole bunch of
squirrels what our investment strategy is the squirrels just want the nut don't we all but
that's where this is so those questions are what do you have to lose if it happens who's going to
be affected and then what's the best way for us to develop not just a theory because it's going to
be uncomfortable whatever that means and I would guess uncomfortable is going to be there's going
to be starving people there's going to be people that aren't going to have a job there's going to
be people that are going to lose their homes the homes that they again yes yes maybe they've
over leverage maybe they went and bought the BMW when they shouldn't have maybe they spent too much
money on their wedding maybe they paid too much for their kids college when college really isn't
going to be a thing at some point in the future maybe all of that happened maybe they made bad
decisions maybe they gambled it away maybe they they're addicted to drugs or alcohol or god knows
what but is that is that really the way we want to do this we're going to start now scoring people
economically viable i know they already do that with the the credit score system and okay yeah
so you have that and of course you don't want to spend you don't want to lend money to people that
are apparently irresponsible but maybe there are reasons why somebody might look irresponsible but
really aren't irresponsible sometimes i mean my god just walking through life you slip and fall
and it wasn't because you did anything wrong it just happened so the moonshot is this my proposal
is this is we build out a moonshot a strategy an idea an entire formulation of assets and ideas and
techniques and and and on purpose focus for the people which would be everybody that's on the
ground floor like everybody like me looking up we develop a transition moonshot what's going to end
up happening i try to keep everybody okay they're laying off people now they haven't been able to
attribute this to mass AI layoffs and maybe this is just maybe this is just pillow talk preparing
us for maybe some eventual what would appear to us on the ground floor being horrible the people
that are at the top that are very very excited about this technology because now they're going
to be able to live for 50 lifetimes instead of just the one because they're building out the
medical technology there's so much here to unpack let's let's work on this together i think we can
i'm connor if you have any more uh if you have any ideas please throw them in the comments if
you're watching this later and thank you very much for watching be well we'll see you tomorrow